you are likely trying to trade too many
different Candlestick patterns I
remember at the beginning of my trading
career I actually learned and tried to
apply over 75 different Candlestick
patterns and you know what that led to a
lot of confusion being completely
overwhelmed and ultimately my trading
account dropping consistently fast
forward to now being a professional
Trader I actually only utilize a couple
of different Candlestick patterns for my
trading and what I want to do in this
video is share with you the Candlestick
pattern I would use if I was starting
out as a brand new Trader and this is a
Candlestick pattern I utilize every day
in my own trading so if that sounds like
something you want to learn go ahead and
click that like button for me go and
subscribe if you are new and I'll catch
you after the intro and display
[Music]
foreign
welcome back and just in case you are
brand new my name is Steven I've been
trading for about a decade and I have
three main missions make money help
other Traders do the same and work up
the courage to go skydiving now this
channel helps me do the first two so
let's go ahead and get started with this
video I believe that this Candlestick
pattern is one of the most slept on
patterns in trading and it's time tested
and you've definitely heard of it before
but I don't think you've applied it to
your trading in the way I'm going to
teach you how to apply it today now just
for context the way I use Candlestick
patterns is for reasons for entry they
are normally the reason I actually click
the buy or sell button after a
Candlestick pattern is formed is when I
do that I use them as my entry reason so
keep that in mind as we go through
today's video and just to show you that
I actually utilize exactly what I'm
teaching you today you can see there's a
live trade going on on the screen right
now on the Euro Yen if you look down
here you can see this is an owonda Live
account I'm about a thousand dollars on
this trade or around a two to one reward
to risk ratio now in this video I'm
going to explain and break down the
entire reason for entering this trade
because there was a lot more to it than
just this one Candlestick pattern and
that way you'll have a full strategy by
the time you leave but for now let's
discuss the actual Candlestick pattern
the engulfing Candlestick pattern now I
know a lot of you have probably heard of
this pattern and may even know how to
spot it on a chart but again I'm going
to be teaching you how I use these
patterns to actually pull profits out of
the market so stick around if you are
that person but if you're brand new and
don't know what this pattern is I want
to go ahead and give you a little
tutorial of it right now so this very
simple pattern is nothing more than the
body of a candle being larger than the
previous body of the previous candle and
it does need to be a color change so
this candle must be red for a bullish
engulfing candle and the engulfing
candle must be green that's how simple
this is it's literally just a candle
stick that has a body bigger than the
previous Candlestick body and again the
color change from red to Green is
necessary for a bullish version of the
engulfing pattern now in stocks the
engulfing pattern needs to have an open
lower than this previous candle and a
close higher than the body of this
previous candle but in Forex what you'll
notice is that most candles open at the
exact point of the previous close and
that's why these candles are drawn this
way so keep that in mind if you trade
stocks but if you trade Forex this is
how they will look so for a bearish
version of this it's completely the
opposite we need the body of this candle
to be larger than the body of the
previous candle we need a color change
from green to red and as long as we have
those two things despite what the Wicks
look like we don't even need to focus on
wicks for this Candlestick pattern
because they do not matter so
irregardless of what the Wicks look like
if we have a green candle followed by a
red candle that's larger the body is
larger than the previous green candle we
have a bearish engulfing candle and if
we have a red candle followed by a green
candle that has a larger body
then that red candle then we have a
bullish engulfing pattern so a lot of
confusion can happen even after learning
a Candlestick pattern and saying I'm
only going to use this Candlestick
pattern and that confusion happens
because you never take the time and it
happened for me because I never took the
time to actually create a very simple
rules-based strategy around that
Candlestick pattern so I would just be
trading it in the middle of nowhere with
no other Confluence and that again
caused a lot of losses for me so what I
want to do now is explain this entire
trade and explain the full way that I
use engulfing Candlestick patterns in
order to actually pull profits out of
the market let's go ahead and get
started so when trading Candlestick
patterns I never trade them without
three other technical confluences you
can pick your own but right now I'm
gonna explain what my technical
influences were for this trade so for
this trade we're out on the daily chart
now I took this trade on the four hour
and for this trade the daily chart is
showing an uptrend so the first
technical factor I had is that we are in
trim to the upside and as a special
bonus to that we also don't have a level
of resistance until
162.67 so we have all this space before
there's a resistance level meaning we
have the possibility of catching a
really big move to the upside but in
terms of this uptrend we have prices
pushing higher
creating a low to a higher high all of
this just being a bit of a complicated
pullback then a push higher and
eventually this break Above This
previous zone of resistance you can call
it consolidation if you want to I'm
calling it a complicated pullback so as
we broke above that level I already knew
I was already prepared for prices coming
back down to this level I'm not going to
buy on this breakout because I'm not
going to chase the market but if we get
a pullback into an area of Interest an
area of value like this major level of
resistance that's been tested multiple
times then that's when I know I have the
best odds of a winning trade so Factor
number one was that we're in an uptrend
with room to the upside if I place a
trade Factor number two was that I
wanted price to come down to a level of
major structure that had been tested
multiple times I call these
otzs or optimal trading zones so we have
Trend we have price in an otz or optimal
Trading Zone that's when I want to drop
down to a trading time frame like the
four hour chart which is what I use and
on the four hour chart I ended up seeing
the RSI indicator going oversold while
in my zone so what we had was the daily
Trend going up we had a daily level of
major structure in that otz I just
showed you and on the four hour chart we
had prices going into an oversold RSI
situation so if we add those up that is
three major technical factors before the
Candlestick pattern which also counts as
a technical Factor so with those three
technical factors in place I knew I was
just waiting on a Candlestick pattern
that Candlestick pattern happened and
was this engulfing pattern right here as
you can see follows the rules of our
bullish engulfing pattern we have a big
green body candle that's got a bigger
body than the previous red candle making
this a valid engulfing pattern and the
reason I decided to actually press the
buy button on on this specific trade so
no single Candlestick that you learn
will ever make you some super profitable
Trader just because of a single
Candlestick in trading we have to
combine a Candlestick formation with
other technical factors in order to
create an edge over the market that
plays out over time keep that part in
mind it plays out over a long span of
time when we have a Candlestick pattern
combined with three other technical
factors that doesn't mean we're gonna
win every single trade we're absolutely
not I don't win every single trade but
what this does is creates an edge that
plays out over a large sample size of
Trades which gives me the ability to be
profitable over a long span of time and
so here's what I want you to try in
conclusion on this video I want you to
try only trading this in a demo account
by the way if you're brand new to
trading or still struggling as a Trader
you don't need to be trading with live
money anyway so this needs to be tried
in a demo account if you're new try this
while you're learning about Pips
leverage while you're learning about
stop losses while you're learning about
risk management and trading psychology
and by the way we have a completely free
basic scores that goes over all that
it's linked in the description or you
can go to the web address you see on the
screen right now but while you're
learning all of those things take what
you just learned about engulfing candles
and use either those three technical
factors or choose your own but use three
different technical factors in
Confluence with a Candlestick pattern
for entry and do that on a demo account
while you learn and see what the outcome
is not over one trade not in one week
see what the outcome is over a large
span of time it'll probably take you one
to three months to learn the basics of
Forex and to have them mastered while
you're doing that just trade this on a
demo account out and see what it comes
up with what do you have to lose and the
only thing that I just remembered that I
did leave out was stops and targets
there's no rocket science to this I
normally put my stop loss below the
engulfing candle somewhere that makes
sense in this case it made sense to put
it below the entire Zone because I could
still get a decent reward to risk ratio
doing that and for targets I normally
set a Target at about a one to a 1.4 to
1 reward risk ratio and if I want to
manage the position I move my stop to
break even once that one to one or one
point four to one is hit and continue to
manage the position on the way up and
the reason I'm doing that in this
specific case not that you need to worry
about that if you're a beginner but the
reason I'm doing this in this specific
case is because of how much room to the
upside we have on the Euro Yin before we
hit the next major level of structure so
even having a full strategy like that is
only about a third of the puzzle that
you need in order to be a professional
Trader so the rest of that puzzle or
triangle
looks a little something like this I
call this the triangle trading success
everyone making money is in the middle
of this triangle and they've mastered
three skills that is a strategy that
makes the money over time that's proven
to be profitable that is a risk
management plan that keeps them from
blowing their account losing too much
money and becoming super emotional and
that is the trading psychology that
keeps them from switching strategies
from moving their stop up and down that
keeps them in an emotionally clear State
while they're trading and you must
master all three of these if you ever
have hopes of making money consistently
as a Trader and as I said earlier we
actually have a completely free
beginners course that'll help you master
all three of these it is linked in the
description or you can go to the web
address you see on the screen now if
you're ready for some more advanced
trading and you want a little more
one-on-one with me to help you along
your path of becoming a profitable
Trader then we have a little bit of room
inside of the TTC Forex University right
now that's our Flagship course and if
you want all the details of that and
what's included in that course all you
gotta do is go to the top Link in the
description or go to
www.ttcfxuniversity.com if not that's
completely fine too just be sure you're
subscribed here to keep up with all the
free content we come out with be sure
you click the like button if you got
some value from it comment if you made
it to the end and I'll catch you in the
next video see you soon